import 'package:quiz_app_tutorial/models/question.dart';

const List<Question> techQuestions = [
  Question(
    question: '1. Who co-founded Microsoft along with Bill Gates?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Steve Jobs',
      'b) Mark Zuckerberg',
      'c) Paul Allen',
      'd) Larry Page',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '2. What does the acronym "HTML" stand for?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) HyperText Markup Language',
      'b) High Tech Multi-Language',
      'c) Home Tool Markup Language',
      'd) Hyperlink and Text Markup Language',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '3. Who is the CEO of Tesla, Inc.?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Jeff Bezos',
      'b) Elon Musk',
      'c) Tim Cook',
      'd) Sundar Pichai',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '4. What programming language is often used for developing Android apps?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Swift',
      'b) C++',
      'c) Java',
      'd) C#',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '5. Which company developed the first commercially available computer mouse?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) IBM',
      'b) Microsoft',
      'c) Xerox',
      'd) Apple',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '6. What does the acronym "AI" stand for in the context of technology?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Advanced Internet',
      'b) Artificial Intelligence',
      'c) Automated Information',
      'd) Augmented Interface',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '7. In computer terminology, what does "RAM" stand for?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Random Access Memory',
      'b) Read-Only Memory',
      'c) Rapid Application Management',
      'd) Real-time Analysis Module',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '8. Who is the co-founder of Apple Inc. alongside Steve Jobs?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Bill Gates',
      'b) Mark Zuckerberg',
      'c) Larry Page',
      'd) Steve Wozniak',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '9. What does "URL" stand for in web addresses?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Universal Resource Locator',
      'b) Uniform Resource Locator',
      'c) Unified Resource Locator',
      'd) Universal Reference Locator',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '10. Which social media platform was known for its 140-character limit posts before 2017?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Twitter',
      'b) Facebook',
      'c) Instagram',
      'd) LinkedIn',
    ],
  ),
];
